I'm taking you off this case, Kogami.
今回の捜査から外れてもらうぞ　狡噛
The body was eroded
by a special kind of chemical.
遺体は特殊な薬剤に浸食され
Analysis confirmed that
the chemical used in this case
これは３年前の事件で使われた薬品と同一であることが判明した
was the same one that was
used in the case three years ago.
謎の殺人鬼が３年ぶりにカムバックってわけか
So after three years, the mysterious
homicidal maniac has come back, huh?
この男
This man...
The picture's filename was..."Makishima."
画像ファイルのタイトルは 「マキシマ」だった
My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
Can I flush out the truth?
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
Secret remains for you
Don't expose these false colors and futures
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 TMR@10 校对:西西   后期:时末
#08 And Then,  Silence
The security...
警備体制…一段と厳しくなりましたね
...has gotten really tight, hasn't it?
Two students fell victim in short succession
相次いで２人もの生徒が 同じ手口の犯罪の餌食になった
to crimes that had the same MO.
If the academy doesn't take action,
they'll have to answer to the parents.
これで学園側が何の対策も講じなければ 保護者が黙っていないよ
In addition, the suspect is Kouzaburou Touma,
a former teacher at this school.
加えて　容疑者は元教諭の藤間幸三郎
That narrows the MWPSB's investigation
公安局の捜査の焦点も ここ桜霜学園に絞り込まれる
down to this school, Ousou Academy.
I guess I'm bound hand and foot for a while.
しばらく身動きが取れませんわね
Why did you only choose students
within this school for your works of art?
なぜ　同じ学園内の生徒ばかりを素材に選んだのかな
This academy is a girls' boarding school.
全寮制女子学校というこの学園の教育方針を槙島先生はどうお考えですか
What do you think of their
education policy, Mr. Makishima?
It's out of date, but because of that,
there's value in its rareness... perhaps.
時代錯誤ではあるが それ故に希少価値がある…かな
If parents want their daughters
to receive an education
今の時代になおも 昔ながらのスタイルで娘に修学させたいと思うなら
in an old-style environment in this day and age,
this is the only choice they have.
ここしか他にない
Chastity and grace...
Traditional virtues that have been lost...
貞淑さと気品 失われた伝統の美徳
They comprise the educational
ideology of Ousou Academy.
それが桜霜学園の掲げる教育の理念
They're priorities that are
not valued in boys, only in girls.
男子には求められない 女子だけに付加されるプライオリティー
After having them instilled in us,
それを刻み付けられた後で
we're shipped out as a brand-name
product, "refined, sheltered maidens,"
私たちは深窓の令嬢というブランド品として出荷され
and purchased by men who seek
a classic piece of furniture called
そして　良妻賢母というクラシックな家具を求める殿方に購入される
"a good wife and mother"...
...in a formality known as marriage.
結婚という体裁でね
Students in this school are all components
この学校にいる生徒は誰もが
that will be processed
into an artwork called the "lady."
淑女という名の工芸品に加工されるための素材なんです
They are rough stones waiting to
be polished and finished up.
磨き上げられ 完成されるのを待つ原石
They live sad and boring lives...
悲しく そして退屈な命ですわ
...even though there are many
other possible ways they could bloom.
他に花開くはずの可能性はいくらだってあるのに
That's an interesting perspective.
So that's the foundation for your art, huh?
面白い見解ではある そこに君の初期衝動があるわけか
Once you finish your new work,
where are you going to exhibit it this time?
新しい作品を仕上げたら　今度はどこに展示するつもりだい
Let's see... I wonder where would be good...
そうですね　どこがいいかしら
I have to find a lively place that
attracts many people's attention.
なるべく大勢の目に付くにぎやかな場所を探さないと
No leads at all, huh?
手掛かりは皆無か
And, here's the grim new developments.
さらに笑えない新情報
I heard there are two Year 2 students
who disappeared from the dorm.
２年生で２人ばかり寮から消えた生徒がいるそうで
The school contacted their
parents' homes, but they aren't there.
実家に問い合わせても帰宅してない
They've gone completely missing.
完璧に行方不明っすよ
At any rate, it's strange.
しかし妙な話だな
Both the campus and dorm are in a
lockdown more akin to a military facility.
校舎も学生寮も軍事施設並みの厳戒態勢
Is it even possible for him to
take his victims out of this place?
ここから犠牲者を連れ出す方法なんてあるのか
To start with,
そもそも なぜ今になって桜霜学園の生徒ばかりを標的にする
why does he only target
Ousou Academy students now?
To Touma, this school
is his old nest so to speak.
藤間にとってこの学園は いわば古巣です
Maybe he knows a secret
path that can bypass security.
どこか警備の穴になる抜け道を知っていたのかも
That's very possible.
あり得ますよね
This academy is what, 100 years old?
この学園 創設１００年でしたっけ
Buildings on the premises have
gone through numerous renovations
敷地の中増減築の繰り返しで 見取り図とかもひどいもんっすよ
so their blueprints look terrible, too.
Could it be possible... that the
murder site and the killer's hideout
まさか　殺しの現場もホシの隠れ家も 全部学園の中ってことはないですか
both lie inside the academy's premises?
I knew it was information on the case!
やっぱり事件の情報
This is Ms. Karanomori's doing, isn't it?
唐之杜さんの仕業ですね
What do you think? You've been
reading the reports, too, right?
どう思う
あんたも目を通してはいるんだろ
What do I think? Well...
どうって言われても…
Based on the analysis of the chemicals,
I could only think that the possibility
薬剤の分析結果からも３年前の事件と同一犯の可能性が高まったとしか
has increased that this is the
same culprit from three years ago.
My thought was the total opposite of that.
俺はまったく逆の感想を抱いた
Opposite?
逆
Yeah. In the case three years ago...
ああ　３年前の事件だと 例えばこいつだ
For example, see this guy.
One of the victims.
犠牲者の一人 汚職疑惑のかかった衆院議員でな
He was a Lower House
member suspected of corruption.
He was suspected of submitting falsified
reports of his Crime Coefficient too,
犯罪係数の虚偽申告も疑われたが再計測を拒否
but he refused to have it re-measured.
When the media and the
opposition parties questioned him,
マスコミや野党の追及を「記憶にございません」とか
he tried to dodge the questions
with clichéd answers like, "I don't recall."
カビの生えた言葉で切り抜けようとした
Then, he was found dead...
それが死体で発見された
...with his skull cleanly cut open
and his brain completely gouged out.
頭蓋骨が奇麗にカットされて脳がすっぽりくりぬかれた状態でな
His hippocampus, the part of the brain
that plays an important role in memory,
被害者の肛門には　記憶について重要な働きをするとされる脳のパーツ
had been inserted into his anus.
海馬が突っ込まれていた
How Sasayama was killed suggested this too,
佐々山の殺され方もそうだが あのときの犯人は
but it seems that the culprit then wanted
殺し方や死体の飾り方に 何らかの意味合いを持たせようとしている節があった
the ways he killed and exhibited the
bodies to convey some sort of message.
There were four victims.
The places their bodies were found were...
被害者は４人 死体が発見された場所はホログラフ·イルミネーションの裏側
...underneath a Holographic illumination,
a luxury Japanese-style restaurant,
高級料亭　動物園
a zoo, and right above a
stage set up for an idol's concert.
アイドルがライブ用に組んだステージの真上
But this time, both bodies were found in a park.
しかし今回は２件続けて公園だ
The setup is boring.
舞台設定に芸がない
Boring...
芸って
I don't sense any crooked humor
or message from these two murders.
今回の２件からはゆがんだユーモアやメッセージ性も感じない
They're beautiful and devilish,
and look like works of art,
美しく悪魔的で芸術作品のようだが 何かが致命的に欠けている
but something critical is missing.
What is this something?
何かとは
Originality...
オリジナリティー
Originality... you say?
オリジナリティーですか
Despite such elaborate murders,
the culprit isn't sending a strong message.
こんな手間をかけた殺しなのに 犯人の主張が薄い
At least, I don't sense it.
少なくとも俺には感じられない
To Kouzaburou Touma, killing people
was just about preparing materials.
藤間幸三郎にとって殺しは ただの素材の下準備でしかなかった
Up to that point, it's the same
in the current murder case.
そこまでは今回の殺しも共通だ
But from that point...
だがそこから先は
...the ways they worked on
the bodies are totally different.
死体の作風というか まるで違う
I get a totally different
picture of the culprit.
まったく別の犯人像が見えてくる
He's highly intelligent
知能が高くシビュラ判定では 高収入の職業を割り当てられている
and is assigned to a job with
a high income by Sibyl's Judgment.
But he's quite young...
しかしかなり若い
...or he's someone whose mental age is young.
もしくは精神年齢が低い人物
Considering the bodies didn't
show many indignities of a sexual nature,
死体を性的に侮辱する要素の少ないことから
we can guess that
he wasn't abused as a child.
幼児期の虐待は受けていないと推測できる
Is that...
それは
Sort of like profiling.
プロファイリングもどき
Inspector, I'm applying
for permission to go out.
監視官　外出許可を申請する
What? But I have to go with you.
それって私が同伴しないと…
Right, so I'm saying come with me.
だからついてこいと言ってるんだ
"Tokorozawa Correction and Rehabilitation Center"
This place is...
ここは
Is this your first time coming here?
来るのは初めてか
Well, I guess you'd have no
reason to come, huh?
足を運ぶ理由もないか
Once you or Gino decides that I'm useless,
あんたやギノから役立たずだと判断されたら
I'll be thrown in here and will
never be able to leave again.
俺はここに放り込まれて二度と出てこられなくなる
But what on earth are we doing here?
でも　こんな所に来て いったい何を
If my hunch is correct,
the ways the bodies were arranged
俺の直感が正しければ 今回の死体の加工にはきっと元ネタがある
in the current case are
based on some original work.
So I'll ask an expert in that field about it.
だからその筋の専門家に話を聞く
From this point, patients with severe conditions
この先は　犯罪係数３００以上の重篤患者が隔離されている
who have Crime Coefficients
over 300 are kept isolated.
In case of emergency, poisonous
gas is released through the vents.
有事の際には通風口から毒ガスが出る仕組みだ
So this place can be turned
into an execution chamber any time.
ここはいつだって 処刑室に早変わりするわけさ
そんな…
That's terrible...
Even if these guys could go outside,
こいつらは 外に出られたとしても
they'd just immediately get an
execution verdict by the Dominators
即刻ドミネーターに処刑宣告を食らって
and end up as mincemeat.
ミンチにされるだけの連中だ
At least by staying behind bars,
they get to stay alive.
生きていられるだけ おりの中の方がましさ
Oh hi, Doggie. Long time no see.
あ～ら ワンコちゃん　お久しぶり
I see you've done a lot
more drawings since the last time.
ずいぶんと絵が増えた
I bet adding them to
your back is tough even for you.
さすがに背中は無理だろう
It may not look it,
but my body is quite flexible.
こう見えても体は柔らかいのよ私
If I have a mirror,
I can do it on my back.
鏡さえあれば背中もいけるわ
Have you been watching the news?
ニュース見てるか
I'm not interested in a world that
doesn't show an understanding of art.
芸術に理解のない世界なんて興味はないのよ
I'm looking for artwork
that's similar to these bodies.
この死体に類似性のある作品を捜している
Paintings, sculptures, films, comics...
Even literature is fine, too.
絵画　彫刻　映像　漫画 文芸作品でも構わない
Oh, they're pretty good.
あ～ら いい出来じゃない
They're exactly like Rouichi Ouryou's art.
王陵牢一のアートそのまんま
Do you know the name?
知ってるか
No.
いえ
To think that even the name
Rouichi Ouryou has faded away...
王陵牢一の名前も残らないなんて…
Back in the day, even if
the art was designated harmful,
昔はたとえ有害指定食らっても
someone would protect it in the net archives.
誰かがネットのアーカイブで保護したもんだけどね
Are there no longer
any kids with guts like that?
そういう根性のある子は もういないの
People like that would be behind bars
with you, thanks to the Sibyl System.
そんなやつは お前と一緒に塀の中さ
シビュラシステムさまさまだ
You're coldhearted, Ko.
冷たいのね　コウちゃん
Here. Doesn't it look the same?
は～い　そっくりでしょ
"Special Edition"
"Rouichi Ouryou Draws 'My Daughter'"
In my store, too, his artwork sold for good money.
私の店でも彼の作品にはいい値が付いたわ
It was because they
were not superficial, trendy art.
浮ついたはやり物じゃなくて
Instead, they contained
firm fundamental themes.
きちんと根源的なテーマが見て取れたからよね
Thanks, that was a big help.
助かったぜ
Let's check the investigation materials.
捜査資料から検索だ
Does Rouichi Ouryou bring up anything?
王陵牢一 何か引っ掛かる項目がないか
Let's see... there's a student at
Ousou Academy whose last name is the same.
えっと　桜霜学園に 同じ名字の生徒が在籍してます
Mr. Kogami! She's blood related to him!
この子 血縁者ですよ　狡噛さん
Have you seen any suspicious people?
不審な人物を見掛けたりとかは
No.
いえ
I see... then...
そうですか　それなら…
K-Ko!
コ…コウ
Ah...
That idiot!
あのバカ
Please wait! There's a
suspect among the students!
待ってください
生徒の中に容疑者がいるんです
Huh?
Hey! What do you think you're doing?!
君　いったい何のまねかね
We requested repeatedly that you be
very considerate during the investigation
生徒たちをいたずらに刺激しないよう
捜査活動にはじゅうぶん配慮しろと再三 こちらは…
in order not to get the students
worked up unnecessarily!
You are Rikako Ouryou, right?
王陵璃華子だな
What about it?
それが何か
Crime Coefficient is 472.
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「犯罪係数　４７２」
「執行モードリーサル·エリミネーター」
Aim carefully and eliminate the target.
「慎重に照準を定め…」
What're you doing?!
何をする！
Stop it!
やめんか！
A-Are you guys insane?! She's a minor!
しょ…正気か？貴様ら　未成年者を相手に…
Well, teacher... we don't
have Juvenile Law these days.
先生 今少年法とかないんですわ
That was close.
間一髪でしたね
Thanks. Did Mr. Makishima also arrange this?
助かったわ　これも槙島先生の計らい？
Yes.
ええ
Blockade the entire academy right away!
今すぐ学園全域を封鎖しろ
Use all the Drones we've got!
ありったけのドローンを動員だ
We don't have enough? Do something!
数が足りない？何とかしろ！
That's... Kagami...
これって加賀美？
How is it possible that
we can't find one single girl?!
小娘一人捜し出すこともできないってのはどういうことだ！
The security here is very
strict when coming in and going out,
ここ　出入りに対するセキュリティーばっかり厳重で
but when it comes to finding someone
hiding inside, there are a ton of holes.
いざ中でかくれんぼとなるとざるもいいとこなんすよ
Using the records from the security
cameras over the past several days,
過去数日分の監視カメラの録画から
can you pick up just Rikako Ouryou?
王陵璃華子の姿だけをピックアップできるか？
If we get support from the lab at Headquarters,
本部のラボに支援させれば
that kind of image search can be done quickly.
その程度の画像検索はすぐにでも
Do it.
やってくれ
In any case, Rouichi Ouryou, you said?
しかし　王陵牢一だと？
How did you find out such an artist existed?
そんな絵描きがいたなんてどうして分かった？
Originality, right, Mr. Kogami?
オリジナリティーですよね？狡噛さん
What?
何だって？
Well, that's because... the message
the culprit was sending was boring,
いや　だからその…
犯人のメッセージ性に芸がないから
so... by profiling, uhm...
その　プロファイリングによって…ですね
Kogami...
狡噛　今回の２件は藤間幸三郎の犯行でないと
...did you know that these two murders
were not by Kouzaburou Touma
お前は最初から見抜いていたのか？
from the start?
The culprit this time decided where
to exhibit bodies based solely on
今回の犯人はただ目に付けばいいというだけで
whether or not it
catches people's attention.
遺体の陳列場所を決めていた
Kouzaburou Touma would
never pick a park twice in a row.
２回続けて公園を選ぶなんて
藤間幸三郎だったらあり得ない
Even so, we still can't say for sure
that it was all done by Rikako Ouryou.
だからといって　まだ全てが王陵璃華子の仕業だとは…
Either way...
どうであれ　あんな犯罪係数をマークした娘を放っておくわけにはいかない
...we can't leave a girl who registered
such a high Crime Coefficient be.
Right?
そうだろ？
Image search completed.
I'll browse through them.
画像検索完了
ブラウズするわね
Oh... looks like she's a sociable girl.
ああ　社交的な子だったんだな
Her followers are always with her.
常に取り巻きがついてる
Where's this camera?
どこのカメラだ？
The garbage disposal facility
behind the dorm.
寮の裏手にあるごみ処理施設ね
What was she doing in a place like that?
こんな所に何の用が？
Kogami...
「狡噛　今回の２件は藤間幸三郎の犯行でないと
...did you know that these two murders
were not by Kouzaburou Touma
お前は最初から見抜いていたのか？」
from the start?
The culprit this time decided where
to exhibit bodies based solely on
「今回の犯人はただ目に付けばいいというだけで
whether or not it catches people's attention.
遺体の陳列場所を決めていた」
Mr. Shibata, so you like music?
柴田先生は音楽がお好きなのですか
Yes. I'm always looking for new artists.
ええ　いつも新しいアーティストを探しています
I really enjoy finding interesting new talent.
興味深い新人を見つけるのが本当に楽しみで
A-Assistant Principal!
きょ…教頭先生！が…学園内から
Student bodies have been
found on the academy's premises!
生徒の死体が！
What?!
何ですって！？
So you were close to her, huh?
大事な友達だったのね
You can tell?
分かりますか？
Yeah, from the look on your face.
顔を見ればね
I failed to tell her something important.
私はあの子に大事なことを伝え損ねました
She kept talking about Yoshika...
「葦歌　葦歌」って
She wasn't thinking about me at all.
全然私のことなんか気にしてくれなくて
I was the one who
suggested she ask Rikako Ouryou.
王陵璃華子に相談しろって
あの子に勧めたのは私なんです
I shouldn't have let her go alone!
１人で行かせるべきじゃなかったんです
It's as if I killed her myself!
私が殺したようなものです
Cry while you can...
or your Hue will get cloudy.
今のうちに泣いておきなさい
じゃないと色相が濁っちゃうわよ
There are too many
things that can't be explained.
説明のつかないことが多過ぎる
Rikako Ouryou's escape route...
That equipment in the basement...
王陵璃華子の逃走経路 あの地下室の設備
No matter how you look at it,
どう考えても女子高生一人が賄いきれるものじゃない
these aren't things that a female
high school student can prepare by herself.
There's something going on
behind the scenes this time, too.
今回も裏に何かある
It's possible that, like you said...
ひょっとするとお前の言うとおり…
This is odd.
おかしい
What's the matter?
どうした？
There's some damaged data.
破損してるデータがある
When Kunizuka did the search earlier,
all the recordings were fine.
さっき六合塚が検索したときにはどの録画も無事だった
Looks like the damage was focused
on the art room camera's data.
美術室のカメラのデータが
集中的にやられてるな
It's all been destroyed...
全滅か…
No, this one... Looks like
we can restore the sound.
いやこいつ 音声は修復できそうだ
Why did you only choose students
within this school for your works of art?
「なぜ　同じ学園内の生徒ばかりを素材に選んだのかな？」
This academy is a girls' boarding school.
「全寮制女子学校というこの学園の教育方針を槙島先生はどうお考えですか？」
What do you think of their
education policy, Mr. Makishima?
Is this really the correct route?
本当にこのルートで確かなのね
Choe Gu-Sung?
チェ·グソン
Just in case, I'd like to ask you
a question before this is all over.
念のため最後に質問しておきたい
Rikako Ouryou...
王陵璃華子　なぜ僕を失望させることになったのか
...do you yourself realize how
you came to disappoint me?
君自身に自覚はあるかな？
Wh-What are you talking about?
What on earth did I do?
な…何の話です？
私がいったい何を？
Well... if you don't realize it,
then I guess you can't even reflect on it.
うん　自覚がなければ反省のしようもない
As I suspected, it seems that I can't
expect any more growth from you.
やはり君にはこれ以上の成長は期待できないようだ
It's unfortunate. At first,
I thought you had a bright future.
残念だよ
初めはもっと前途の有望な子だと思っていたんだが
Teacher... Mr. Makishima!
What on earth do you mean?
先生…槙島先生
いったいどういうことなんですか？
I think this is a line by Tamora,
the Queen of Goths.
ゴートの女王　タモーラのせりふだったかな？
"So should I rob my sweet sons of their fee:
「カワイイ息子たちからのご褒美を奪うことになる」
No, let them satisfy their lust on thee."
「あの子たちの情欲は満たしてやらねば」
No service
Unable to access network
Wh-What's going on?
な…何なの？
"The hunt is up, the morn is bright and grey,
「さあ　狩りが始まるぞ」
「白々明けの朝」
The fields are fragrant
and the woods are green:
「野原はかぐわしき香り」
「森の緑は濃い」
Uncouple here and let us make a bay."
「ここで猟犬を解き放ち 声高く吠えさせよう」
"They told me, here,
at dead time of the night,
「真夜中になるとここは 何千もの悪魔やシューシューと威嚇の音を立てる蛇
A thousand fiends, a thousand hissing snakes,
Ten thousand swelling toads, as many urchins,
何万もの小鬼や体の膨れ上がったヒキガエルどもが集まって
Would make such fearful and confused cries."
身の毛もよだつ狂乱の叫びを上げる」
"Listen, fair madam: let it be your glory
「この女の涙を見るのはあなたの名誉になる」
To see her tears; but be your heart to them
「ただし　心を火打ち石にして 涙の雨垂れなどはね返すこと」
As unrelenting flint to drops of rain."
Rouichi Ouryou
No service
Unable to access network
"So, now go tell, an if thy tongue can speak,
「さて　その舌でしゃべれるなら告発するがいい」
Who 'twas that cut
thy tongue and ravish'd thee."
「誰に舌を切られ 誰に犯されたか 思いの丈を書いて訴えるがいい」
"Write down thy mind, bewray thy meaning so,
An if thy stumps will let thee play the scribe."
「その２つの切り株で字が書けるなら」
You too will be discarded eventually
when Mr. Makishima gets bored of you.
あなただって
いずれ槙島先生が飽きたら捨てられる
You don't have to worry about that.
ご心配なく
It seems that you were a
fox cub providing entertainment,
君は楽しませる側の子ギツネだったようだが
but just like him, I'm one of the
players who enjoy the entertainment.
私は彼と同じく楽しむ側のプレーヤーでね
"Her life was beast-like, and devoid of pity;
「この女の生涯は野獣に似て 哀れみに欠けていた」
And, being so, shall have like want of pity."
「死んだ今は野鳥程度の哀れみが似つかわしい」
Was it okay? You really liked her, right?
いいんですか？
あの子　結構お気に入りだったんでしょうに
Yeah... but I found a more interesting toy.
ああ　もっと面白いおもちゃが見つかったからね
I'd like you to gather some information.
ちょっと情報を集めてほしい
The man from the MWPSB who
came to the academy this afternoon.
昼間学校に来ていた公安局のおそらくは執行官
He's probably an Enforcer.
It seems his name is Kogami.
コウガミというそうだ
That's quite an unusual
guy you've set your sights on.
そりゃまた妙なやつに目を付けましたね
Yeah.
His insight and ability
to grasp... Quite interesting...
あの洞察力と理解力とても興味深い
I get the feeling he'll be very entertaining.
きっと楽しませてくれるんじゃないかな
Looks like the fairy tale
died a moment ago
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
I was born behind black iron bars
Wish for payback for the evil done
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
Before you destroy and get destroyed
Pay karma's price and have your revenge,
Monster without even a name
Make the sky pour down black rain
I'm not wanted
I cracked and had a breakdown
To my beloved partners
in crime looking on
Now exhibit your justice
Treasuring those permanent scars
I'll accept this
body and go together with you,
Monster without a name
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.